<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.</description>
   <language>en_GB</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>8 Reasons Why Better Nutrition Makes You a Better Developer</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2013/07/18/8-reasons-why-better-nutrition-makes-you-a-better-developer/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-07-18T11:03:03+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2013/07/18/8-reasons-why-better-nutrition-makes-you-a-better-developer/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Ref: <a href="https://thecodebarbarian.wordpress.com/2013/06/21/8-reasons-why-better-nutrition-makes-you-a-better-developer/">8 Reasons Why Better Nutrition Makes You a Better Developer</a></p>

<p>So this one isn&#39;t from me, but I thought it was worth giving some love to on here. Definitely worth the few minutes to read through and stuff that I very much agree with. Many thanks to <a href="https://thecodebarbarian.wordpress.com/about/">Valeri Karpov</a> over at <a href="https://thecodebarbarian.wordpress.com/">The Code Barbarian</a> for putting together such an epic piece!</p>

<p>As you may (or may not) already know, I&#39;ve been doing the paleo thing for about a year now, following the <a href="https://www.bulletproofexec.com/the-complete-illustrated-one-page-bulletproof-diet/">Bulletproof diet</a> by Dave Asprey, and thanks to it i&#39;m pretty much feeling the best I have in as long as I can remember.</p>

<p><a href="https://thecodebarbarian.wordpress.com/2013/06/21/8-reasons-why-better-nutrition-makes-you-a-better-developer/">Read the full article</a> at the link.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Software developers are not known for having the best nutrition. When it comes to development work, the stereotypical late night Red Bull-fueled coding binge is often not too far from the truth. It...</p>
</blockquote>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
