<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.</description>
   <language>en_GB</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Shared Devices Need Account Switching</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2016/08/31/shared-devices-need-account-switching/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-31T00:00:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2016/08/31/shared-devices-need-account-switching/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Living in share houses and using tech like the Apple TV has highlighted an annoying situation: so many apps these days want you to sign in to enable access, personalised features, etc; but most offer no good solution for when you share the device with other people.</p>

<p>There are some apps out there that handle this pretty well:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.plex.tv/">Plex</a> allows you to switch between different users in your &#39;home&#39;, each of which can either be a fully independent account, or a &#39;managed user&#39; that exists under the main account.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.netflix.com/au/">Netflix</a> allows switching between different users under the one subscription. While this is ok.. it doesn&#39;t work so well for a share house. What if we each have our own Netflix subscriptions, but want to share the device without having to log out and back in to our own accounts?</li>
</ul>

<p>And then there are so many apps that don&#39;t even seem to give the option, two of which immediately jump to mind for me:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/">YouTube</a> let&#39;s you sign in to a single account, but no switching features save for logging out.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.ted.com/">TED</a>&#39;s app suffers from the same issue.</li>
</ul>

<p>This could be fixed at the individual app level. It would be REALLY nice to see support for multiple account switching added to any app made for a device that could potentially be shared (Apple TV/etc, far less likely to be useful on an iPhone.. but it might be for some users) But this requires extra effort from every app developer out there. Perhaps a common framework could be developed to help support this.. but then making it generic enough to fit into everyone&#39;s different architectures would be a challenge.</p>

<p>An even better solution could be baked into the OS itself by Apple.. I boot up my Apple TV and am presented with an account chooser asking which particular registered user I am. If I haven&#39;t already logged in, there&#39;s the option for signing in to my Apple account to add myself as a new user. Once logged in, I&#39;m presented with my own homescreen of apps, laid out to my own preferences, logged in to my own accounts, and saving my own personal data.</p>

<p>This poses some issues about duplication of apps between users, space requirements, etc. So a mid-ground could be allowing the owner/&#39;master&#39; user to control app installation, but then for each other user to be able to maintain their own stored data/signin status/etc.</p>

<p>What do you think? Is this a feature you&#39;d use, or does it just seem like over-engineered bloat? Let me know your thoughts in the comments!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
