<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.</description>
   <language>en_GB</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Squiz Matrix: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2017/09/07/squiz-matrix-multiple-vulnerabilities/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2017-09-07T00:00:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2017/09/07/squiz-matrix-multiple-vulnerabilities/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Earlier this year I had an opportunity to spend some time looking at <a href="https://www.squiz.net/technology/cms">Squiz Matrix</a>, a Content Management System (CMS) used across a number of sectors including higher eduction, media and publishing, goverment, finance, health, and utilities. With a huge number of features, a massive PHP codebase, and a numbr of high profile sectors as clients, I set out to see if I could find any interesting little bugs hidden away.</p>

<p>While I won&#39;t get into the nitty gritty of most of the assessment process, I did find some things, and 3 CVE&#39;s were assigned (detailed below). One was interesting enough that I will probably write up the process in more detail at some point.</p>

<p>Given the rich functionality and plugins in the Matrix product, it could be interesting to dedicate more research time to explore the areas I didn&#39;t get to cover this time around. Who knows, perhaps Squiz would even be open to setting up a Bug Bounty program through someone like <a href="https://www.bugcrowd.com/">Bugcrowd</a> in the future too. That would be cool!</p>

<p>If you want to try it out, or play around yourself, there is a <a href="https://matrix.squiz.net/releases/vm">downloadable demo VM</a> available on the Squiz website.</p>

<h2>The CVE&#39;s</h2>

<ul>
<li><strong>CVE-2017-14196</strong>: An information disclosure caused by a Path Traversal issue in the &#39;File Bridge&#39; plugin allowed the existence of files outside of the bridged path to be confirmed.</li>
<li><strong>CVE-2017-14197</strong>: Multiple reflected Cross-Site Scripting (XSS) issues in Matrix &#39;WYSIWYG&#39; plugins.</li>
<li><strong>CVE-2017-14198</strong>: Authenticated users with permissions to edit design assets can cause Remote Code Execution (RCE) via a maliciously crafted <code>time_format</code> tag.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Remediation</h2>

<p>TODO: Include details about vulnerable versions and when it was fixed here (should also be in the CVE details already)</p>

<h2>CVE-2017-14198: A Walkthrough</h2>

<p>TODO: Write up how this was identified, and the core issue that lead to it.</p>

<h2>Acknowledgements</h2>

<p>These issues were identified by <a href="http://devalias.net">myself</a> and the team at <a href="https://dtss.com.au">TSS</a>:</p>

<ul>
<li>Glenn &#39;devalias&#39; Grant (<a href="http://devalias.net">http://devalias.net</a>) of TSS (<a href="https://dtss.com.au">https://dtss.com.au</a>)</li>
</ul>

<p>Special thanks to Micky at Squiz for being an amazing resource throughout the disclosure process, and keeping us informed as patching and rollout progressed.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>It seems the core issues here were a few bugs popping up in legacy code, and passing user-controlled values into sensitive areas without proper checks/sanitisation. Easy mistakes to make when managing such a large codebase that has evolved over the years.</p>

<p>Have you had a similar experience? Manage a large codebase and legacy code? Got good tips for how best to identify and avoid these sorts of issues? Would love to hear your ideas in the comments!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
