<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>https://www.devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.</description>
   <language>en_GB</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>What I Use - OSX</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2013/06/20/what-i-use-osx/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-06-20T10:00:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2013/06/20/what-i-use-osx/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I&#39;ve been meaning to write this post for a while now, but never quite got around to it. Oftentimes when a friend or colleague gets a new mac they ask me what programs I would recommend. I tend to stumble at being asked on the spot, and rattle off the couple that jump straight to mind.</p>

<p>To save myself the embarassment, serve as a memory jog, and hopefully help some people out along the way, here is my list of programs I use/love on OSX (see after the break)</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> This isn&#39;t necessarily a definitive list, but it should be the main ones, and I will try to keep it updated as I find new cool things that I love.</p>

<h2>General/System</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://brew.sh/">HomeBrew</a> - Think apt-get, but for mac. Awesome way to find/install commandline tools/etc for your mac.</li>
<li><a href="https://bahoom.com/hyperdock/">HyperDock</a> - Show previews of docked program windows when you hover over them. Just like Windows 7!</li>
<li><a href="http://totalfinder.binaryage.com/">TotalFinder</a> - Tabs and other such win for the finder!</li>
<li><a href="http://totalterminal.binaryage.com/">TotalTerminal</a> - A systemwide terminal that hides offscreen when you&#39;re not using it. Combine the hotkey with BetterTouchTool for epic win!</li>
<li><a href="https://www.boastr.net/">BetterTouchTool</a> - Let&#39;s you setup more touch gestures to control various things on your mac.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.axoniclabs.com/DeepSleep/">DeepSleep</a> - Forces the system to do a full hibernate poweroff. No more losing battery while in your bag!</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/integralpro/nosleep">NoSleep</a> - Prevents the system from sleeping when you close the screen.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.appzapper.com/">AppZapper</a> - The uninstall feature that&#39;s missing from so many mac programs.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Internet/Download/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/">Google Chrome</a> - What can I say, I am very much a fan of Google, and Chrome has won my heart &lt;3</li>
<li><a href="http://ll.www.utorrent.com/intl/en/">uTorrent</a> - For those times when a distributed download is a better source than direct.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Chat/Communication/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.skype.com/en/">Skype</a> - I don&#39;t even need to explain this one..</li>
<li><a href="http://www.kandasoft.com/home/kanda-apps/callnote-skype-call-recorder">Callnote for Skype</a> - Skype recording + Evernote. Because why remember details when you can just listen to them again!</li>
</ul>

<h2>Music/Media/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.apple.com/au/itunes/">iTunes</a> - Apple, music, duh!</li>
<li><a href="https://www.spotify.com/us/">Spotify</a> - I don&#39;t use this a lot yet, but it&#39;s pretty good when you don&#39;t want to specifically decide what you want to listen to.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.videolan.org/vlc/index.html">VLC</a> - The only media player you&#39;ll ever need for video (or when you don&#39;t want to clutter iTunes with random stuff yet)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Games</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://store.steampowered.com/about/">Steam</a> - The only game platform you should ever need.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Notes/Syncing/Cloud/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/">Dropbox</a> - Keeps my files synced/accessible from wherever I need them.</li>
<li><a href="https://evernote.com/">Evernote</a> - Think dropbox, but more aimed at notes/etc. Available anywhere I need access to them.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.xmind.net/">XMind</a> - Not that this fits into the cloud/syncing category by itself (dropbox!), but a good little tool for making mindmaps.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Coding/Development/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://developer.apple.com/xcode/">XCode</a> - Kind of goes without saying. Apple&#39;s de-facto fully integrated coding environment.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2</a> (<a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/3">Sublime Text 3</a> is currently in beta) - Tried a few others, but eventually settled on this. A REALLY nice text/code editor with tons of awesome plugins. I use the Solarized dark colour scheme.</li>
<li><a href="https://git-scm.com/">Git</a> - A free an open source distributed version control system that is made of amazing and win.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.git-legit.org/">Le-git</a> - A complementary command-line interface for Git that makes some of the more obscure things much easier.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.git-tower.com/">Tower</a>/* <a href="http://gitboxapp.com/">Gitbox</a>/* <a href="https://www.sourcetreeapp.com/">Sourcetree</a>/* <a href="https://desktop.github.com/">Github for Mac</a> - Haven&#39;t really decided which one is best yet, but a selection of git frontends for the (rare) times when you want a change from the command line.</li>
<li><a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a> - Only recently started playing with this, but a very nice little web app development framework/environment.</li>
<li><a href="https://toolbelt.heroku.com/">Heroku Toolbelt</a> - Set of command line tools for working with/deploying to Heroku.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Virtualisation/Etc</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.parallels.com/products/desktop/">Parallels Desktop</a> - IMO The better virtualisation platform for mac.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.vmware.com/products/fusion/">VMWare Fusion</a> - For things that just don&#39;t want to work in Parallels, or just for funsies.</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
