<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.
</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Syncing Facebook Bdays/Events with Other Calendars</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2011/10/17/syncing-facebook-bdaysevents-with-other-calendars/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2011-10-17T07:39:00+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2011/10/17/syncing-facebook-bdaysevents-with-other-calendars/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I&#39;m sure i&#39;m not alone when I say that without Facebook events/bdays I would be so much more out of the loop. A while ago I realised that I could subscribe to events/bday feeds in my external calendars (in this case, my iPhone). Best; Day; Ever! Suddenly I don&#39;t need to be at my computer to know what&#39;s going on, which for me is great since I tend to have the &#39;out of sight out of mind&#39; mentality. Even if I looked at them this morning, ask me at midday and I won&#39;t remember a thing I have planned.</p>

<p>In any case, this stopped working for a while, and I finally got around to reenabling it yesterday, so figured I would make a quick post about how to find it for anyone else interested.</p>

<p>Hope you guys enjoy/find it useful! :)</p>

<h2>Facebook Event Feed</h2>

<ul>
<li>Go to <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/">http://www.facebook.com/events/</a></li>
<li>Scroll to the bottom of the page</li>
<li>Click on the export link</li>
<li>Copy the webcal:// link</li>
<li>Go to your favourite calendar application and use it&#39;s subscribe feature, pasting in the copied link (on an iPhone if you just click the link it will add it for you)</li>
</ul>

<h2>Facebook Birthday Feed</h2>

<ul>
<li>Go to <a href="http://www.facebook.com/events/birthdays/">http://www.facebook.com/events/birthdays/</a></li>
<li>Scroll to the bottom of the page</li>
<li>Click on the export birthdays link</li>
<li>Copy the webcal:// link</li>
<li>Go to your favourite calendar application and use it&#39;s subscribe feature, pasting in the copied link (on an iPhone if you just click the link it will add it for you)</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
