<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>My intention is for this to be a place where I post anything that interests my geeky mind. I may not update it often, and you may not find it that interesting.. You've been forewarned.
</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>v3.0 -  Now with more Hyde</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2016/05/22/v3-now-with-more-hyde/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2016-05-22T00:00:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2016/05/22/v3-now-with-more-hyde/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Time for another rebirth! As you may have noticed, I haven&#39;t really written much over the last year or two. While I&#39;ve been busy, distracted and occasionally just lazy, I&#39;ve mostly found that Tumblr&#39;s interface is just far too much effort to write in. And if something is needlessly too much effort, it&#39;s not going to get done.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>, the static website builder. I&#39;ve been intending to put something together on this platform forever.. The first iteration started in <a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> a year or more back, but never really went anywhere since the default theme was kind of ugly. Decided to take another stab at things this year while I was between jobs (free time == productivity!), found a theme that I liked and started hacking away. With a few months of scattered hacking and procrastination, it&#39;s finally actually on the internet, yay!</p>

<p>Being a static site, I&#39;m taking advantage of <a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>. While it gives me free hosting, it also means I&#39;m now living my <a href="/devalias/2012/01/04/resolutions-for-11111011100-2012/">previous mantra</a> of &#39;open source everything&#39;. You can access the <a href="https://github.com/alias1/devalias.net">files used to generate the site</a> and <a href="https://github.com/alias1/devalias.net/issues">create an issue</a>/pull request to fix up any typos/errors you might find along the way :)</p>

<p>Given it&#39;s now only mildly more effort for me to write a post here as it is to save my notes in random text files on my computer, I&#39;ll hopefully put more online.. We shall see.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>New Window With Tabs To Right - Chrome Extension</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2013/08/08/new-window-with-tabs-to-right-chrome-extension/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-08-08T08:00:50+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2013/08/08/new-window-with-tabs-to-right-chrome-extension/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>(tl;dr I wrote a chrome extension, <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/new-window-with-tabs-to-r/ldahcfljppchbfgdokomobmfdfplaman">get it in the web store</a> or <a href="https://github.com/alias1/chrome-NewWindowWithTabsToRight">check it out on GitHub</a>)</p>

<p>So I decided I would re-dip my feet into the wonderful world that is chrome extensions. I had a little look a while back, but never really got to making anything relevant.</p>

<p>This time around I decided to start off simple, and something that I would find useful, so without further ado building up drumroll here is the copypasta of the description I wrote for the chrome web store (there are SO many extra little hoops you have to jump through to go from working code to published in the web store.. Maybe a potential future topic?):</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This is a simple little extension (my first proper one!) that I wanted to make my life a little easier.
It lets you create a new window with the tabs to the right (optionally including the current tab)
My main reason for wanting this was to more effectively make use of the &#39;Sesh&#39; extension by Yuji Kosugi when I forgot to open a new window before opening a ton of tabs.
If you have any comments, criticisms, praise, hatred, marriage proposals, fluffy bunnies, or transdimensional gateway blueprints, feel free to send them through to me at <a href="mailto:feedback@devalias.net">feedback@devalias.net</a> (Make sure to mention the extension name in the subject so I know what you&#39;re talking about!)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Since that&#39;s a blockquote and I can&#39;t link in it, here is a link to <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/sesh/emclpejnhkiogdlimfgipbdfpdcnhhoj">Sesh</a> by <a href="https://about.me/yujily">Yuji Kosugi</a> (highly recommended if you&#39;re a tab junkie like myself!)</p>

<p>So yeah, that&#39;s it! Check it out in the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/new-window-with-tabs-to-r/ldahcfljppchbfgdokomobmfdfplaman">Chrome Web Store</a> and let me know what you think!!</p>

<p>Oh, by the way, since I love you guys and open source software, it&#39;s released under the MIT Licence and you can go and <a href="https://github.com/alias1/chrome-NewWindowWithTabsToRight">check it out over at GitHub</a>! &lt;3</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Resolutions for 11111011100 [2012]</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2012/01/04/resolutions-for-11111011100-2012/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2012-01-04T10:31:00+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2012/01/04/resolutions-for-11111011100-2012/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So here comes the obligatory post about my resolutions for 2012. In no particular order or level of detail:</p>

<ul>
<li>Spend more time hanging out and chatting with friends. Those who are physically close as well as those far away; in person, on the phone and online; those who I am close to and those I should be closer with.</li>
<li>Put more time into coding/web design/development tasks with the aim of getting at least 1 app out this year.</li>
<li>Open source anything and everything I do that isn&#39;t a &#39;trade secret&#39; (More on this to come later). Who knows what people will be able to find a use for. Also contribute back anything I can to open source projects I use.</li>
<li>Continue to read, learn and grow; be it in technical skill, learning about myself, or the world; and share what I learn with everyone and anyone who is interested. (Essentially open source whatever knowledge I gain)</li>
<li>Be more forward and take (calculated) risks even when they seem scary. (Talking to someone new/interesting/cute, giving that project a go, etc)</li>
</ul>

<p>This one isn&#39;t a resolution so much as a goal but a notable thing to do in any case:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ensure all of my hard drives utilise full disk encryption, using a strong password. &#39;&#39;The man&#39; thinks he is too good these days, so why not stick it to him in a simple, fun, and secure way. (See the article on EFF.org)</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
