<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.</description>
   <language>en_GB</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>New Window With Tabs To Right - Chrome Extension</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2013/08/08/new-window-with-tabs-to-right-chrome-extension/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-08-08T08:00:50+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2013/08/08/new-window-with-tabs-to-right-chrome-extension/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>(tl;dr I wrote a chrome extension, <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/new-window-with-tabs-to-r/ldahcfljppchbfgdokomobmfdfplaman">get it in the web store</a> or <a href="https://github.com/alias1/chrome-NewWindowWithTabsToRight">check it out on GitHub</a>)</p>

<p>So I decided I would re-dip my feet into the wonderful world that is chrome extensions. I had a little look a while back, but never really got to making anything relevant.</p>

<p>This time around I decided to start off simple, and something that I would find useful, so without further ado building up drumroll here is the copypasta of the description I wrote for the chrome web store (there are SO many extra little hoops you have to jump through to go from working code to published in the web store.. Maybe a potential future topic?):</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This is a simple little extension (my first proper one!) that I wanted to make my life a little easier.
It lets you create a new window with the tabs to the right (optionally including the current tab)
My main reason for wanting this was to more effectively make use of the &#39;Sesh&#39; extension by Yuji Kosugi when I forgot to open a new window before opening a ton of tabs.
If you have any comments, criticisms, praise, hatred, marriage proposals, fluffy bunnies, or transdimensional gateway blueprints, feel free to send them through to me at <a href="mailto:feedback@devalias.net">feedback@devalias.net</a> (Make sure to mention the extension name in the subject so I know what you&#39;re talking about!)</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Since that&#39;s a blockquote and I can&#39;t link in it, here is a link to <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/sesh/emclpejnhkiogdlimfgipbdfpdcnhhoj">Sesh</a> by <a href="https://about.me/yujily">Yuji Kosugi</a> (highly recommended if you&#39;re a tab junkie like myself!)</p>

<p>So yeah, that&#39;s it! Check it out in the <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/new-window-with-tabs-to-r/ldahcfljppchbfgdokomobmfdfplaman">Chrome Web Store</a> and let me know what you think!!</p>

<p>Oh, by the way, since I love you guys and open source software, it&#39;s released under the MIT Licence and you can go and <a href="https://github.com/alias1/chrome-NewWindowWithTabsToRight">check it out over at GitHub</a>! &lt;3</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
