<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>My intention is for this to be a place where I post anything that interests my geeky mind. I may not update it often, and you may not find it that interesting.. You've been forewarned.
</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Dogedraw, now with more Nyaan!</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2015/04/20/dogedraw-now-with-more-nyaan/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2015-04-20T12:00:00+10:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2015/04/20/dogedraw-now-with-more-nyaan/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Over the last few days I&#39;ve been mentoring web dev at <a href="http://hact.io/">HS.HACT.IO</a>, inspiring a group of younger kids to get into tech as creators. One of the other mentors showed us a site he previously put together, <a href="http://dogedraw.com/">DogeDraw</a>. After playing around with it for a little, I decided it was a little too manual, so started hacking away in the JS console to make it more fun.</p>

<p>A little while (and far too long typing out pixel art as code) later, and we have nyaan hacks! You can clear a section of the screen with a solid block of colour, or better yet, stamp out some pixel art nyaan cat across the page!</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/alias1/e8bb28726a37854606ad.js"> </script>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Resolutions for 11111011100 [2012]</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2012/01/04/resolutions-for-11111011100-2012/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2012-01-04T10:31:00+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2012/01/04/resolutions-for-11111011100-2012/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>So here comes the obligatory post about my resolutions for 2012. In no particular order or level of detail:</p>

<ul>
<li>Spend more time hanging out and chatting with friends. Those who are physically close as well as those far away; in person, on the phone and online; those who I am close to and those I should be closer with.</li>
<li>Put more time into coding/web design/development tasks with the aim of getting at least 1 app out this year.</li>
<li>Open source anything and everything I do that isn&#39;t a &#39;trade secret&#39; (More on this to come later). Who knows what people will be able to find a use for. Also contribute back anything I can to open source projects I use.</li>
<li>Continue to read, learn and grow; be it in technical skill, learning about myself, or the world; and share what I learn with everyone and anyone who is interested. (Essentially open source whatever knowledge I gain)</li>
<li>Be more forward and take (calculated) risks even when they seem scary. (Talking to someone new/interesting/cute, giving that project a go, etc)</li>
</ul>

<p>This one isn&#39;t a resolution so much as a goal but a notable thing to do in any case:</p>

<ul>
<li>Ensure all of my hard drives utilise full disk encryption, using a strong password. &#39;&#39;The man&#39; thinks he is too good these days, so why not stick it to him in a simple, fun, and secure way. (See the article on EFF.org)</li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
