<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.
</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Powering my mobile hacking freedom</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2012/02/29/powering-my-mobile-hacking-freedom/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2012-02-29T04:32:00+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2012/02/29/powering-my-mobile-hacking-freedom/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Over the past 6 months or so I have learnt just how productive I can be working outside of home. I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s the change of scene, having less distractions, or merely that a fresh cup of coffee is only a question away. Perhaps a topic for a future post? One thing is certain though, unless your local haunt has a ready supply of power points (and is happy to let you use them) you&#39;re hack sessions are going to be rather shortlived.</p>

<p>It was for this reason that I decided to invest in an external battery for my laptop, in particular the HyperJuice External Battery for MacBook (150Wh). I should note that there are other sizes available too (60Wh, 100Wh, 222Wh), but for the price/performance tradeoff I decided on this one.</p>

<p>My aim of this post isn&#39;t to write a sales pitch or anything like that, though I must say that I was quite impressed with how sleek the casing design was. Personally I would have much preferred it in a matte black (even if this does match the MacBook Pro unibody better), but I guess beggars can&#39;t be choosers.</p>

<p>Packing 150Wh this thing isn&#39;t exactly what I would call lightweight, weighing in at approx 1.09kg and boasting &quot;up to 34 hours MacBook usage!!!!!&trade;&quot; That is of course if you happen to subscribe to their particular scenario..</p>

<blockquote>
<p>MacBook Pro 13&quot; with 63.5-watt-hour (10 hours) rated internal battery, rounded to the nearest hour. Requires MagSafe Airline Adapter.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>On my MacbookPro 15&quot; with the screen set kind of bright, my iPhone plugged in to the USB port for internet tethering, and a plethora of tabs open in Rockmelt I find the real world usage is rather.. not quite as much. I haven&#39;t actually bothered to work it out properly, but at a rough guess I would say I get between 2-4 hours off my internal battery, and then maybe 2-5 hours off the external. It seems it varies quite a bit too, though I haven&#39;t really looked into why. I am also using the HyperJuice Magic Box to modify my existing MagSafe charger rather than a MagSafe Airline Adapter. Maybe changing to that will cause some magical additional battery life?</p>

<p>Finally, price. At US$350 odd for the 150Wh model this thing isn&#39;t exactly the cheapest piece of tech i&#39;ve ever bought. That being said, the fact that it at least doubles the length of my cafe based hack sessions means i&#39;m pretty ok with it.</p>

<p>All in all i&#39;m pretty impressed with the HyperJuice, though if I had my time again I would probably buy the 222Wh (to help make up the difference between marketing charge life and real world life) Hopefully in the near future someone will bring out something cheaper/more powerful (~$125 per 400Wh/kg), preferably in sandblasted matte black, but until then the HyperJuice is definitely worth a look.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
