<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>devalias.net</title>
   
   <link>http://devalias.net</link>
   <description>Follow me into the rabbit hole that is my mind and learn about topics including.. security, technology, efficiency, biohacking, health, personal growth and probably a whole lot more.
</description>
   <language>en-uk</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Thecus NAS: /dev/alias says no!</title>
	  <link>/devalias/2013/11/28/thecus-nas-devalias-says-no/</link>
	  <author>devalias</author>
	  <pubDate>2013-11-28T15:52:31+11:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>/devalias/2013/11/28/thecus-nas-devalias-says-no/</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>Spent the day today digging around in the deepest and darkest parts of my Thecus NAS, and I can now say absolutely and without a doubt not to waste your money on them.</p>

<p>The filesystem is horrendous, the scripts are hacked together, and it&#39;s overall just really quite disgusting for what is meant to be a SMB/Business grade device.</p>

<p>I also have some serious concerns about the validity of the encryption it makes use of (&#39;backing up&#39; the encryption keyfile and password, encrypted with a static key.. pssht, no thanks) Not to mention that the &#39;&#39;bin&#39; config backup file is just a .tar.gz encrypted with, yet again, a static key.</p>

<p>And for funsies, there are a few things that i&#39;ve seen along the way that I would think are exploitable, at least potentially so. Haven&#39;t really had the time/effort/inclination to delve into it further at this stage.</p>

<p>This is all on top of the fact that support has been HORRENDOUS (I basically have to open a new ticket each time I reply, just to get them to look at my original ticket/attempt to do something)</p>

<p>In positive news.. has been interesting to say the least, and I&#39;m pretty sure I have all the components i&#39;ll require to string my RAID back together into some form of working state. Just a matter of figuring out just how to fit them together..</p>

<p>I might follow this post up in the future with some interesting findings, recovery steps, exploits or otherwise. Till then!</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
